<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: GSOE9820 | Henry Z's blog~]]></title>
  <link href="http://changchen.me/blog/categories/gsoe9820/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://changchen.me/"/>
  <updated>2017-07-17T01:10:05+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://changchen.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Daya]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[daya0576@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GSOE9820 Project Management 16s2]]></title>
    <link href="http://changchen.me/blog/20160811/9820-project-managment/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-11T11:30:39+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://changchen.me/blog/20160811/9820-project-managment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>The second term of my master degree in UNSW       <br/>
This blog is sharing my experience of GSOE9820 Project Management in 16s2</p></blockquote>

<!--more-->


<br>


<blockquote><p>Share your experience about this course through this url:   <br/>
<a href="http://www.unsw.co/rango/category/engineering-project-management/">http://www.unsw.co/rango/category/engineering-project-management/</a></p></blockquote>

<br>


<blockquote><h3>25/07/2016</h3>

<hr />

<p><strong>week1</strong>  <br/>
Everyone said that this course is useless and waste of time.    <br/>
Unfortunately this course is compulsory and not easy to apply exemption.    <br/>
<img style="max-height:132px" class="lazy" data-original="/images/blog/160811_9820/compulsory.png"></p></blockquote>

<br> 


<blockquote><h3>08/08/2016</h3>

<hr />

<p><strong>week3</strong>  <br/>
A fun moment in lecture&hellip;   <br/>
<img style="max-height:450px" class="lazy" data-original="/images/blog/160811_9820/fun.JPG"></p></blockquote>

<br> 


<blockquote><h3>03/09/2016</h3>

<hr />

<p>So so so boring!!!   <br/>
Some times you even have the illusion that this managment knowledge is somehow useful&hellip;   <br/>
<img style="max-height:400px" class="lazy" data-original="/images/blog/160811_9820/illusion.png"></p></blockquote>

<br> 


<blockquote><h3>16/09/2016</h3>

<hr />

<p>Lecturer&rsquo;s feedback of project3~~  <br/>
I&rsquo;m the PM of that project :)  <br/>
<strong>Kun Dong</strong> <br/>
Very late on Q1/Q2. All three posts within 21 minutes and all very brief. This points to one thing alone, and that is poor preparation and participation.  <br/>
Q3 was similar in that 3 of 4 posts were within 28 minutes and all three posts were brief.  <br/>
Q4 – all three posts within 12 minutes and they were even briefer.  <br/>
Feedback on Final Report.  <br/>
This is a sub-par effort and I think you know it. Please return to your previous form.  <br/>
_   <br/>
<strong>Xiang Li</strong> <br/>
Feedback on Project Plan. Q1/2 – good participation, but always with very brief contributions.      <br/>
Q3 – One good post, the rest brief or ‘I agree’ posts. Q4 – same as Q3 and less.      <br/>
Feedback on Final Report.      <br/>
This was a disappointing result, after two god projects.   <br/>
_      <br/>
<strong>Han Peng</strong>      <br/>
Q1 and Q2 – Three very brief posts within an hour and they were late and a final post on the second last day.      <br/>
Q3 you provided good answers to this question, but Q4 was very light on.      <br/>
Feedback on Final Report.      <br/>
_   <br/>
<strong>Yiming Wang</strong>      <br/>
Feedback on Project Plan and Final Report.      <br/>
Good participation and contribution in all the questions. Not quite the same level as the previous two projects and that is mainly due to a lower level of contribution rather than participation.      <br/>
_   <br/>
<strong>Changjian Zhu &ndash; PM</strong>              <br/>
You published a good Project Plan and on time. Great facilitation and follow u of the plan. You chased Xiang, Kun and Han.   <br/>
Great participation, discussion, feedback and contribution. Your summaries were excellent. However, there was a definite slowdown during the last two questions.   <br/>
A draft Final Report was published a day ahead.   <br/>
The Final Report was very good, but could have had much better formatting.   <br/>
All in all a great job. Well done PM.</p></blockquote>

<br> 



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
